<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Lucas Neves Pereira</title>
    <link>https://lucasnp.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Lucas Neves Pereira</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucasnp.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lembra</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/projects/lembra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/projects/lembra/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a desktop app with Wails &amp; Vue</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/posts/build-a-desktop-app-with-wails-and-vue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 10:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/posts/build-a-desktop-app-with-wails-and-vue/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! In this post I want to show how to quickly setup a desktop app using this amazing Go library Wails.
Basically, Wails allows to write desktop softwares using web technologies like Angular, React, Vue, Svelte..
Installing Wails Getting started with this library is quite easy, if you have all the prerequesites you just need to run a go get to install it in your local machine, if you need details this is going to add wails to the pkg directory of your GOPATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Migrations with Cobra &amp; Golang Migrate</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/posts/sql-migrations-with-cobra-and-golang-migrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 12:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/posts/sql-migrations-with-cobra-and-golang-migrate/</guid>
      <description>Hello dear readers, lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to run database migrations in Golang with sqlite3 but I have found a solution and I want to share it with you guys.
Let&amp;rsquo;s do this Start by creating a simple project Golang project in your computer
mkdir migration-cli cd migration-cli go mod init migration-cli Then get the cobra package
go get -u github.com/spf13/cobra Open this in your favourite code editor and create and add a main.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gituser CLI - Switch between git accounts easily</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/posts/gituser-cli-switch-between-git-accounts-easily/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 12:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/posts/gituser-cli-switch-between-git-accounts-easily/</guid>
      <description>Hello there 🙂
First of all you all may be wondering &amp;ldquo;What in the world is gituser??&amp;rdquo;
Gituser is a command line interface made with Golang that helps to switch between different git user accounts.
I have built this cli because I was using my laptop for my personal projects, my school projects and my work related projects. Meaning I had multiple git user accounts in my machine.
Every time I had to type the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write a Simple REST API in Golang</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/posts/write-a-simple-rest-api-in-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 12:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/posts/write-a-simple-rest-api-in-golang/</guid>
      <description>Hello there 😀
In this brief article I will explain how I write a REST API using Golang trying to follow some best practices.
The source code to follow along if needed is here.
Let&amp;rsquo;s do this 👍🏻 As an example we&amp;rsquo;ll be creating a very simple Post API.
Structure the project Let&amp;rsquo;s jump to our terminal and create a new directory for our project and then init a go module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitUser CLI</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/projects/gituser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/projects/gituser/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement testing in Golang</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/posts/implement-testing-in-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 13:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/posts/implement-testing-in-golang/</guid>
      <description>Hello dear readers, being a Junior to Mid Developer myself I&amp;rsquo;ve been of course faced to this weird &amp;ldquo;fear&amp;rdquo; of testing my code. Maybe it isn&amp;rsquo;t fear, maybe we just do not talk much about it.
But either way I&amp;rsquo;ve been recently learning to program in Golang and I want it to do it seriously, in the right way. That&amp;rsquo;s why this time I did not skip the tests subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumme Builder</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/projects/resumme-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/projects/resumme-builder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy custom Strapi API connected to an Angular App</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/posts/deploy-custom-strapi-api-connected-to-an-angular-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/posts/deploy-custom-strapi-api-connected-to-an-angular-app/</guid>
      <description>Hello there, before starting this article I want to give you a bit of context. So, I wrote an article about how to build a custom API with Strapi and fetch it from an Angular app. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it i&amp;rsquo;ll link it right above 🙂.
Connect custom Strapi API to an Angular App
This article is a part 2 of that article as I am going to deploy the API on Heroku and the Angular app on Netlify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect custom Strapi API to an Angular App</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/posts/connect-custom-strapi-api-to-an-angular-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 10:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/posts/connect-custom-strapi-api-to-an-angular-app/</guid>
      <description>I recently decided to rebuild my portfolio with Angular. The problem is that I wanted to easily post and update my projects, I first thought about build an NodeJS/Express API connected with MongoDB but this can be time consuming for me knowing that I have others side projects with a lot of work to do.
I decided to take a look into headless CMS, that&amp;rsquo;s when I find out aboutStrapi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn your basics or steps to be a successful Junior Developer</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/posts/learn-your-basics-or-steps-to-be-a-successful-junior-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 18:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/posts/learn-your-basics-or-steps-to-be-a-successful-junior-developer/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Zan on Unsplash
Hello I&amp;rsquo;m Lucas, I started Web Development last year and I work now at my first web developer job. I started web development with HTML5/CSS3 and then moved on directly to PHP and JavaScript . Well this is cool but I realized at my job that I was really missing a lot of basics and foundations about computer science and programming in general. If you do not have a mathematical / engineering background sometimes this can be challenging at your first job, because you&amp;rsquo;re just missing basics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello there 👋🏼</title>
      <link>https://lucasnp.com/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucasnp.com/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Lucas, a software developer living in Paris, France.
I seek to deepen my knowledge and skills on a daily basis, and I truly believe that one of the best ways to learn is by helping other developers, like myself, address issues.
Interested in Web technologies, Open-source projects, Command Line Interfaces and in whatever my curiosity leads me to in the future.
You can find all of my posts on my website, as well as on dev.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
